# JAMES HARGREAVES

Birchwood, Lochgoilhead, Argyll, PA24 8AJ | M: 07792 942935 | E: jameshargreaves1@gmail.com

Development portfolio available at www.jameshargreaves.tech

#### Personal Statement

I am an enthusiastic and highly motivated individual with a passion for learning. I bring a host of transferable skills from my previous roles including excellent interpersonal skills and a great eye for detail having worked in a number of regulated roles.

I have spent the last five years learning to write code in various languages alongside running an e-commerce business as a partner, which we have now decided to close down. Along with daily use of HTML and CSS over the last ten years I gained my first taste of programming when I became interested in writing automated financial trading algorithms around five years ago in C / C++.

Having absolutely loved this period of learning I decided that I would like to continue and decided to enrol on the notoriously challenging CS50 computer science course remotely via Harvard's online portal to give me a more rounded knowledge of computer science and exposure to other languages and technologies including C, Python, Javascript and SQL amongst others. The course was extremely challenging and greatly helped in rounding out my knowledge of programming including data structures, encryption and low level programming.

During Covid, with the downturn our business experienced I decided to look at software / web development seriously as a future career and started to focus heavily on learning Javascript and it's associated technologies. I have increased my knowledge to cover React as well as NodeJS and Express and have since gained experience with GraphQL, MongoDB and Dart/Flutter from a six month internship at a family member's SAAS startup.

I continue to love the challenge of learning and increasing my knowledge in this field. My experience in the industry last year only further cemented the fact that I feel that development is where my future career lies.

### **Employment History**

# 6 Month Internship - Junior Software Developer Dot On Technologies

(2022)

I approached Dot On for an internship position to get some real industry experience and further develop my skills in a broad range of technologies whilst working as part of a development team.

This experience was invaluable as it exposed me to all parts of the development process from back-end through to UI whist collaborating with a team using Jira / Git / Bitbucket - experience I could not have gained working on my own projects.

#### Mv tasks included:

- Refactoring existing codebase and adding new features as required.
- Writing unit / integration tests in Javascript and Dart using Jest and Dart's built in testing suite.
- Working with a MongoDB database using NodeJS / GraphQL / Apollo Server.
- Improving documentation where possible and making sure code comments are up to date and inline with company specifications.
- Working with a back end API and associated documentation / specification.

### Technologies used:

Javascript, Dart, Flutter, NodeJS, GraphQL, MongoDB, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Sourcetree.

# Partner, E-commerce Business Sparkle Boutique

(2012 to Present)

- Dealing with all aspects of day to day running of a small e-commerce business.
- Using HTML and CSS to create product listings and templates.
- Uploading products to website / online marketplaces.
- · Maintaining detailed records both for internal assessment as well as external bodies such as HMRC.
- · Producing daily sales reports and monitoring stock levels across the business.
- Dealing with customers and providing detailed product information and quotations.
- Responsible for the entire logistics process from customer enquiry through to dispatch of orders.

### **Mortgage Adviser**

Royal Bank of Scotland / Countrywide / Homeloan Partnership

(2007 to 2012)

# **Commercial Recruitment Consultant Blue Arrow Ltd**

(2005 to 2007)

# IT Technical Support / Account Manager RAPID IT Distribution / Computer Commodities

(2000 to 2005)

### **Education**

### **Harvard via Edx** (2022 - 2023)

CS50X - introduction to Computer Science - Pass 100%

### Clitheroe Royal Grammar School Sixth Form College (1995 - 1997)

A-LEVEL grade C	Business Studies
A-LEVEL grade C	Design and Technology
A 1 = 1 = 1 = 0	<b>-</b>

A-LEVEL grade C Biology

A-LEVEL grade C General Studies

## Clitheroe Royal Grammar School (1990 - 1995)

GCSE grade A\* / A\* Science (Double Award)

GCSE grade A Mathematics
GCSE grade A English

GCSE grade A English Literature
GCSE grade A Design and Technology

GCSE grade A French GCSE grade B History

GCSE grade B Art and Design
GCSE grade B Physical Education

### References

References are available upon request.